嘿伙计
hey folks
迈克和妮可和务实的工作室
mike and nicole here with the pragmatic studio
你可以做很多很酷的事情
you could do a bunch of cool things
使用 Elixir 编程语言
with the elixir programming language
从使用 Phoenix 框架构建 Web 应用程序
from building web apps using the Phoenix framework
在网络设备上嵌入代码
to embedding code on network devices
并且很想向右跳
and is tempting just to jump right
进入这些并希望最好
into these and hope for the best
但是elixir是一种功能并发语言
but elixir is a functional concurrent language
它需要一个
and it requires a
进入这些新世界的不同思维方式
different way of thinking to enter these new worlds
在本课程中
in this course
您将学习如何自信地使用 elixir 进行开发
you'll learn how to develop with elixir confidently
平稳沉降
for smooth settling
现在，如果您来自 oo 编程背景
now if you're coming from an oo programming background
过渡到函数式编程可以
making the transition to functional programming can
颠簸
be a bumpy ride
但好在
but the good thing is
这不是会让你失望的语法
it isn't the syntax that's going to throw you
事实上，如果你是一名 Ruby 程序员
in fact if you're a ruby programmer
很多长生不老药的语法会让人感觉很熟悉
a lot of elixir syntax is going to feel familiar
不同的是你的想法
what's different is how you think
关于 o 中的编程
about programming in o
您正在考虑的程序围绕对象进行
programs you're thinking revolves around objects
您可以通过调用方法来修改其状态
whose state you can modify by calling methods
但在长生不老药中，所有数据都是不可变的
but in elixir all data is immutable
所以你会更多地考虑转换数据
so you think more in terms of transforming data
带功能
with functions
http web 服务器非常棒
an http web server is a great
灵药做事方式的例子
example of the elixir way of doing things
在高水平
at a high level
Web 服务器只接受一个请求，然后
a web server just takes a request and
通过一系列的转变
through some series of transformations
产生响应
produces a response
事实证明
and it turns out
构建一个简单的 Web 服务器非常棒
that building a simple web server is a great
学习灵药的方法
way to learn elixir
因为它需要我们
as it requires us
使用一个整体
to use a whole
一堆长生不老药特性和功能设计概念
bunch of elixir features and functional design concepts
并通过逐步建立
and by incrementally building
这个应用程序贯穿整个课程
this app throughout the course
您将获得使用 elixir 的实践经验
you'll gain practical experience with elixir
并了解所有部分如何组合在一起
and learn how all the pieces fit together
开发一个完整的长生不老药应用程序
to develop a complete elixir app
作为额外的奖励
as an added bonus
如果您打算使用 Phoenix Web 框架
if you're planning to use the Phoenix web framework
你会有更好的
you'll have a better
了解它的设计方式
understanding of how it's designed
所以事不宜迟，让我们开始吧
so without further delay let's get started